Guide to the Fanny Howe Papers, 1980-1990
Department of Special Collections
Howe, Fanny. Papers,
1980-1990
M0768
Howe, Fanny
2 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Correspondence, family history, literary manuscripts of Fanny Howe
Administrative Information
Access
None.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 1995.
Provenance
Purchased, 1995.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Correspondence, family history, literary manuscripts.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Armantrout,Rae, 1947-; Auster, Paul, 1947-; Banks, Russell, 1940-; Bernstein, Charles, 1950-; Blitz, Michael.; Brown, Harriet, 1958-; Brustein, Robert Sanford, 1927-; Cardenoso, Cecilio.; Chester, Laura.; Clark, Tom.; Corbett, William, 1942-; Creeley, Robert, 1926-; Cuddihy, Michael.; Dahlen, Beverly.; Davidson, Michael, 1944-; Davis, Lydia.; De Lissovoy, Peter.; Flaherty, Joe.; Fraser, Kathleen, 1937-; Gander, Forrest, 1956-; Greenfield, Amy.; Griffith, Sarah.; Grossman, Judith, 1937-; Harper, Michael, 1931-; Hartz, J.; Harryman, Carla.; Hejinian, Lyn.; Hickman, Leland.; Hicks, Kevin.; Howe, Helen Huntington.; Howe, Tina.; Kaplan, Felicia.; Killian, Kevin.; Kraman, Cynthia, 1950-; McPherson, James M.; McShane, Frank.; Major, Clarence.; Mayer, Bernadette.; Messerli, Douglas, 1947-; Norman, Howard A.; Owen, Maureen, 1943-; Palmer, Michael.; Paradiso, Peter.; Rodefer, Stephen.; Sandy, Steve.; Silliman, Ronald, 1946-; Simic, Charles, 1938-; Soling, Caytha.; Tate, James, 1943-; Vaeth, Kim, 1952-; Valentine, Jean.; Verdicchio, Pasquale, 1954-; Warsh, Lewis.; Watten, Barrett.; Williams, Jonathan, 1929-; Williamson, Anne.; Wise, Kelly.; Wright, Carol, (Carol S.); Young, Geoffrey.; Zucker, Ilona.
Collection Contents
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Armantrout, Rae, (2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Auster, Paul, (1) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Banks, Russell, (2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Blitz,Michael, (1) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brown, Harriet (1) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Brustein, Robert, (2) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cardenoso, Cecilio, (1) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chester, Laura, (3) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clark,Tom, (2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clark,Tom 1982, (3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Clark,Tom 1983, (8) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Clark,Tom 1984, (5) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Clark,Tom 1985-1987, (6) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Corbett, William, (5) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Creeley, Robert, (1) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cuddihy, Michael, (2) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dahien, Beverly, (2) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Davidson, Michael, (9) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Davis, Lydia, (1) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - de Lissovoy, Peter, (2) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Flaherty, Joe, (1) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Fraser, Kathleen, (3) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Gander, Forrest n.d.-1986, (5) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Gander, Forrest 1987, (5) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Gander, Forrest 1988, (1) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Greenfleld, Amy, (1) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Griffith, Sarah, (1) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Grossman, Judith, (1) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Harper, Michael, (1) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hartz, [J.], (1) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hejinian, Lyn, (6) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Hickman, Leland, (1) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Hicks, Kevin, (1) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Howe, Tina, (1) ~ (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - [Jucker], (1) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Kaplan, Felicia, (2) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Killian, Kevin (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Kraman, Cynthia, (3) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - McPherson, James1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - McPherson, James 1986-1987, (5) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Major, CLarence, (3) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Messerli, Douglas, (1) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Norman, Howard, (1) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Owen, Maureen, (2) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Palmer, Michael, (3) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Paradiso, Peter, (1) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Sandy, Steve, (1) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Shaw, [], (envelope only) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Silliman, Ron, (2) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Simic, Charles, (1) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Soling, Caytha, (1) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Tate, James, (3) (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Vaeth,Kim, (1) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Valentine, Jean, (1) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Verdicchio, Pasquale, (1) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Warsh, Lewis, (6) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Watten, Barrett, (8) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Williamson, Anne, (1) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Wise, Kelly, (1) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Wright, Carol, (1) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Young, Geoffrey, (1) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Unknown: Bob (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Harryman, Carla, (2) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - McShane, Frank, (1) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Unknown, (1) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Unknown, (1) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bernstein, Charles, (1) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Mayer, Bernadette 1982, (3) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Mayer, Bernadette 1983, (5) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Mayer, Bernadette 1984, (4) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mayer, Bernadette 1984, (3) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Mayer, Bernadette 1985, (3) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Mayer, Bernadette 1986, (3) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Rodefer, Stephen (1) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Williams, Jonathan (1) (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Series II: Family History
  - Inventroy of Howe collection (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Howe, Helen Huntington: A Poor Innocent Young, photocopy of typed MS (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Howe, Helen Huntington: A Poor Innocent Young, photocopy of typed MS (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Howe, Helen Huntington: A Poor Innocent Young, photocopy of typed MS (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Howe, Helen Huntington: A Poor Innocent Young, photocopy of typed MS (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Howe, Helen: diary and letters, 1923, photocopies of typed excerpts (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Howe, Helen Huntington: A Poor Innocent Young, 1924, photocopy of typed MS (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Howe, Helen Huntington: A Poor Innocent Young, 1924, photocopy of typed MS (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Howe, Helen Huntington: A Poor Innocent Young, 1926, photocopy of typed MS (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Howe, Helen Huntington: A Poor Innocent Young, 1928-1929, photocopy of typed MS (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Howe, Helen Huntington: A Poor Innocent Young, 1934-1935, photocopy of typed MS (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Howe, Helen Huntington: A Poor Innocent Young, 1973, photocopy of typed MS (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Howe, Helen: memorabilia (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Marquand, John P.: letters,1933-1934, photocopies of typed excerpts (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Marquand, John P, obituary and article, photocopies (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Sedgwick, Christina Davenport: letters, 1937-1954, photocopies of typed excerpt (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Series III: Poetry
  - "Dead Sea Fruit,", typed MS (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "Did I Do That?" typed MS (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - "Dream Lover" and "Cherry from the North Pole,", typed MS (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - "For Erato," QU7 1982 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - "Twenty-Three Years Later,", photocopied MS with corrections (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - [untitled], typed MS with corrections (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Series IV: Books
  - BMX RCR, autograph draft (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - BMX RCR, typed MS (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - BMX RCR, typed MS (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Famous Questions, typed MS (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Famous Questions, typed MS (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Famous Questions, typed MS (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Famous Questions, typed MS (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Famous Questions; Error Analysis; The Stillorgan Road, autograph draft (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Stillorgan Road, typed MS (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Stillorgan Road, typed MS (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Stillorgan Road, typed MS (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Series V: Essays, Articles and Reviews
  - "Clarence Major: poet and languiage man,", typed MS (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Dentalphobia,", photocopy of typed MS (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "Ho Hum,", photocopy of typed MS (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "How to be Good in the City,", photocopy of typed MS (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - "Inventing Motherhood,", typed MS (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "Notes on Travel,", typed MS (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - "Of Time and the Children,", typed MS (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "The Old Liberals,", typed MS (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "The Poetry of Maureen Owen,", photocopy of typed MS (Box 5, Folder 17)